<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Troop534.org]]></title>
  <link href="http://troop534.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://troop534.org/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-08T21:59:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://troop534.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Boy Scouts of America - Troop 534 "Hey!"]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice Hike Schedule, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/04/08/practice-hike-schedule-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T20:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2013/04/08/practice-hike-schedule-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first and second practice hikes went well for our troop. We have two more practice hikes before the Lincoln Trail:</p>

<ul>
<li>Sat, April 13, 2013 at 8am (11.0 miles, turnaround at Navy Pier)</li>
<li>Sat, April 20, 2013 at 8am (5.5 miles, turnaround at Shedd Aquarium)</li>
</ul>


<p>Every hike starts at 39th Street and Lake Shore Drive. We begin stretching promptly at 8am, and we start hiking immeditely after that.</p>

<p>See you there!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Practice Hike, 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/03/29/first-practice-hike/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-29T17:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2013/03/29/first-practice-hike</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="425" height="550" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" align="right" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=39th+Street+Beach,+1199+East+Oakwood+Boulevard,+Chicago,+IL+60653&amp;daddr=Shedd+Aquarium+John+G,+South+Lake+Shore+Drive,+Chicago,+IL&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FeQ0fgId2lTH-ikxlfEL6CsOiDH1Ow2H0Fhpnw%3BFRbXfgIdACDH-iHf-1Df450FMin5dbdfYysOiDHf-1Df450FMg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Schedd+Ac&amp;sll=41.846002,-87.606542&amp;sspn=0.05243,0.06197&amp;t=h&amp;dirflg=w&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=41.845972,-87.606525&amp;spn=0.041406,0.016007&amp;output=embed"></iframe>


<br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=embed&amp;saddr=39th+Street+Beach,+1199+East+Oakwood+Boulevard,+Chicago,+IL+60653&amp;daddr=Shedd+Aquarium+John+G,+South+Lake+Shore+Drive,+Chicago,+IL&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FeQ0fgId2lTH-ikxlfEL6CsOiDH1Ow2H0Fhpnw%3BFRbXfgIdACDH-iHf-1Df450FMin5dbdfYysOiDHf-1Df450FMg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Schedd+Ac&amp;sll=41.846002,-87.606542&amp;sspn=0.05243,0.06197&amp;t=h&amp;dirflg=w&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=41.845972,-87.606525&amp;spn=0.041406,0.016007" style="color:#0000FF;text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small>


<p>The first practice hike for the Lincoln Trail will begin at 8:00am on Saturday, March 30, 2013.</p>

<ul>
<li>Start: 39th Street &amp; Lake Shore Drive</li>
<li>Turnaround: Shedd Acquarium</li>
<li>End: 39th Street &amp; Lake Shore Drive</li>
<li>Distance = 6.6 miles.</li>
<li>Estimated Completion time: 11am, depending on the pace of the slowest Scout</li>
</ul>


<p>Please arrive before 8am. We will spend ten minutes stretching, and we will hit the trail immediately after that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Message from President Obama]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/03/04/message-from-president-obama/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-04T18:04:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2013/03/04/message-from-president-obama</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Eagle Scout Matthew Gully received the following congratulatory message
from President Barack Obama and First Lady Michelle Obama.</p>

<p><img src="http://troop534.org/images/PresObama-EagleScoutGully.jpg" align="center" width="600" height="414" alt="President Obama's Message to Eagle Scout Matthew Gully" title="President Obama's Message to Eagle Scout Matthew Gully"></p>

<p>Congratulations Eagle Scout Gully, and to your family as well!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Video: How a BMW Gets Made]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/02/18/video-how-a-bmw-gets-made/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T17:49:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2013/02/18/video-how-a-bmw-gets-made</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>How does a BMW get built? What roles are played by robotics, and which
functions are managed by human hands? See the answers for yourself in
this 15-minute video:</p>

<iframe name="bmw-robotics" width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/libw1rV2McY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>The video was shared by Edward Hightower, Founder and Managing Director of <a href="http://motoringventures.com/">Motoring Ventures</a>. Hightower earned the rank of Eagle in Troop 534 &#8220;Hey!&#8221; in 1979. He holds a B. S. in General Engineering from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, and an MBA from the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor.</p>

<p>Mr. Hightower visits Chicago from time to time. Scouts who plan to pursue a career in the automotive industry should make it a point to meet him.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kohl's Cares Scholarship Program]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/02/11/kohls-cares-scholarship-program/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T19:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2013/02/11/kohls-cares-scholarship-program</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/02/11/kohls-cares-scholarship-program/"><img src="http://troop534.org/images/kohls_cares.png" alt="Kohl's Scholarships" title="Kohls's Scholarships" height="112" width="277" align="right"></a>
Kohl&#8217;s is offering scholarships for young volunteers who do great work in
the community. Members of Boy Scout Troop 534 &#8220;Hey!&#8221; are very service
oriented. Therefore, some of our Scouts might be eligibile for these
scholarships.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>For more information, visit <a
href="http://kohlskids.com">KohlsKids.com</a> before March 15, 2013.</p>

<p><img src="http://troop534.org/images/kohls_scholarship.jpg" alt="Kohl's Scholarships" title="Kohls's Scholarships" height="1017" width="800" align="center"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dr. Roderick Claybrooks on Minimally Invasive Surgery]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2013/01/12/dr-roderick-claybrooks-on-minimally-invasive-surgery/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-12T14:47:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2013/01/12/dr-roderick-claybrooks-on-minimally-invasive-surgery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dr. Roderick Claybrooks is an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthopedic_surgery">orthopedic spine surgeon</a>.</p>

<p>In this 9-minute video, Dr. Claybrooks reviews the advantages of minimally invasive surgery.</p>

<center><iframe name="drclaybrooks" width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rNyKSNUR608?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center>


<!--more-->


<p>Minimally invasive surgery is an advanced technique whereby the surgeon makes fewer and smaller incisions in the patient&#8217;s body. A minimally invasive incision might be 20mm (less than one inch) in size.</p>

<p>When the incision is smaller the patient benefits in many ways, including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Less blood loss</li>
<li>Shorter hospital stays</li>
<li>Quicker recovery time</li>
<li>Less anesthesia</li>
</ul>


<p>In summary, minimally invasive surgery enables patients to recover faster. To learn more, consult your physician.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arduino Imagination]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2012/12/13/arduino-imagination/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T17:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2012/12/13/arduino-imagination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Members of Explorer Post 2534 are building projects based on the <a href="http://arduino.cc">Arduino</a> microcontroller. What is Arduino? Several Arduino-based projects are shown in this 15-minute video:</p>

<center><iframe name="arduinoimagination" width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UoBUXOOdLXY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center>


<!--more-->


<p><img src="http://troop534.org/images/arduino_explorers.jpg" width="400" height="255" align="right" alt="Presenting Arduino Projects" title="Presenting Arduino Projects">
After being introduced to the Arduino, each member of the Post was given some time to research possible projects for the device. One by one they stood before their peers to describe their ideas.</p>

<p>Massimo Banzi, co-founder of the Arduino Project, says it best: &#8220;If you have an idea, just go and make it. You don&#8217;t need anybody&#8217;s permission to create something great.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Year Old Guest at M.I.T.]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2012/11/25/15-year-old-at-mit/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T13:07:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2012/11/25/15-year-old-at-mit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kelvin Doe builds batteries and radio transmitters from spare parts that he finds in the trash. He&#8217;s 15 years old and he lives in Sierra Leone.</p>

<center><iframe name="djfocus" width="560" height="315"
src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XOLOLrUBRBY" frameborder="0"
allowfullscreen></iframe></center>


<p>Kelvin recently spent three weeks at the Massechusetts
Institute of Technology as a guest of the MIT Media Lab. His friends call him &#8220;DJ Focus&#8221; because he believes in focus. Well done, Kelvin!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Founded in 1919]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2012/09/17/founded-in-1919/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T21:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2012/09/17/founded-in-1919</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Newly recovered records show that Boy Scout Troop 534 &#8220;Hey!&#8221; was founded
in October 1919, not 1938 as previously believed. The records were discovered by Scoutmaster Emeritus Robert T. Sublette, Sr. and Assistant Scoutmaster
Norville Carter. One page is shown here:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="http://troop534.org/images/1919.jpg" width="550" alt="Troop 534 founded in 1919 in Chicago, IL, USA" title="Troop 534 founded in 1919 in Chicago, IL, USA" ></p>

<p>More research is in order!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Planting Seeds &amp; Building Leaders]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2011/02/14/planting-seeds-and-building-leaders/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-14T19:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2011/02/14/planting-seeds-and-building-leaders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Eleven new Eagle Scouts were recognized on Sunday, Feb 13, 2011. The honorees are members of Troop 534, an organization that has produced 72 Eagles since 1938.</p>

<center><iframe name="11eagles" title="YouTube video player" width="560" height="349" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Hqs2hjB0g6A?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></center>


<!-- more -->


<h3>Eagle Scouts: An Elite Group</h3>

<p>Fewer than three percent (3%) of those who enter Scouting make it to the rank of Eagle. Scouts who earn the rank have learned skills such as wilderness survival, first aid, entrepreneurship, citizenship, and investing. Leadership skills are tested when the Eagle candidate assembles a team of fellow scouts to complete a service project.</p>

<h3>Teamwork &amp; Positive Results</h3>

<p>Troop 534 is led by Scoutmaster Eddie L. Banks, Sr. and a dedicated group of adult volunteers. <a href="http://stmarkumcchicago.org">St. Mark United Methodist Church</a> has provided meeting space and valuable support for over 70 years.</p>

<p>Thank you ABC 7 Chicago for coming out to cover the ceremony.</p>

<p>Our society grows stronger when we give our youth positive life experiences. Everybody wins when that happens. Congratulations Eagles!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu Lab Built by Scouts]]></title>
    <link href="http://troop534.org/blog/2010/12/26/ubuntu-lab-built-by-scouts/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-26T19:39:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://troop534.org/blog/2010/12/26/ubuntu-lab-built-by-scouts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://troop534.org/images/ubuntu.png" border="0" alt="image" name="image" class="right" width="200" height="90" />Members of Boy Scout Troop 534 chose <a href="http://ubuntu.com">Ubuntu</a> for a new computer lab. The project was led by a 16-year-old Eagle candidate, Raymond Westbrook. St. Mark United Methodist Church in Chicago, IL provided the room and six ancient Intel-based PCs.</p>

<p>Raymond Westbrook chose the following people for his project team:</p>

<p><li>Four of his fellow scouts ranging in age from 11 to 17.</li>
<li>The maintenance supervisor of the church, critical in choosing the best path for cable runs.</li>
<li>Three adult advisors: Troop leaders who happen to work in information technology.</li></p>

<h3>Hardware</h3>

<p>Several old systems became available when the church upgraded its computers earlier this year. Raymond learned about the old hardware just as he was deciding what to do for his <a href="http://troop534.org/assets/eagle_project.pdf">Eagle service project</a>. He developed a plan, presented it to the leadership of the church and the troop, and they approved. Then Raymond Westbrook&#8217;s team got busy.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Glitches</h3>

<p>Every project has its challenges. One machine appeared to have a dead hard drive, but opening the unit revealed a loose ribbon cable. Problem solved. The team found a dead power supply in another unit. The machine is too old to justify purchasing a new power supply, so that box will serve as an &#8220;organ donor&#8221; for the other computers.</p>

<p><img src="http://troop534.org/images/ubuntu_lab.jpg" border="0" alt="image" name="image" class="right" width="300" height="177" /></p>

<h3>Ubuntu Installation</h3>

<p>The team downloaded &amp; burned a Live CD of Ubuntu version 10.04. It&#8217;s possible to run directly from the Live CD, but for faster performance it&#8217;s better to install Ubuntu on the hard drive. The project leader likes speed, so he chose hard drive installation.</p>

<h3>Why Ubuntu?</h3>

<p>Ubuntu is a distribution of Linux, a free operating system that preforms many of the same tasks as Microsoft Windows or Apple MacOS. Anyone can download a free copy of Ubuntu at <a href="http://ubuntu.com">http://ubuntu.com</a>.</p>

<p>Ubuntu is open source software. Open source defies common sense because:</p>

<p><li>It&#8217;s free.</li>
<li>You get much more than you pay for.</li>
<li>By contributing time &amp; talent to open source, each person makes things better for all people.</li></p>

<p>Sounds like some crazy hippie madness from the sixties, right? Well&#8230; Google, Yahoo, Facebook, and many other successful tech companies run on open source software. A <a href="http://www.wisdomgroup.com/report/what_is_open_source/">two-page newsletter</a> tells more about the movement.</p>

<h3>Producers vs Consumers</h3>

<p>Some computer labs spend tons of money on the latest hardware and proprietary software to teach youth how to use a word processor or a spreadsheet. What a waste. When we do that to our youth, we&#8217;re just creating the next generation of consumers. America has too many consumers. We need producers!</p>

<p>If we teach our youth about open source software, if we give them the tools to get under the covers to see how the software works, if we encourage them to create something with what they learn&#8230; then we&#8217;re raising <em>producers</em>. Our world needs producers because producers have the skills and drive to make an economy grow. That&#8217;s good.</p>

<h3>Future</h3>

<p>What&#8217;s next? St. Mark plans to make the lab available to members of the church and the neighboring community, especially the youth. After school programs continue to fall under the budget knife. Programs created by St. Mark and the Boy Scouts are here to fill in some gaps.</p>

<p>Earlier this year Raymond shared a story about classmates who teased him for being a nerd. &#8220;That&#8217;s okay&#8221;, Raymond replied. &#8220;You&#8217;re gonna ask me for a job one day.&#8221;</p>

<p>Well put, Raymond Westbrook!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
